So you assessed and cleaned this entire clinical trial data set.
现在你已经评估并清理好了整个临床试验数据集
Let's flash forward to the key point here.
现在我们先提前说一下关键点
Is Auralin, the proposed new oral insulin, effective?
我们推荐的这款新型口服胰岛素 Auralin 有效吗？
Again, that's a comparison to the injectable insulin Novodra.
还是一样 比较对象是注射型胰岛素 Novodra
And here are the clinical trials key metrics.
这里是临床试验的关键指标
The first one here: Adverse reactions.
第一个是 不良反应
For Auralin to pass this Phase II clinical trial it must be deemed safe,
如果 Auralin 要通过 II 期临床试验 其安全性就需得到认可
and the adverse reactions to it is encouraging.
从这里的不良反应来看 希望很大
These adverse reactions were actually previously standalone,
实际上这些不良反应之前是单独列出的
but you join this to the treatments table to allow for this analysis.
不过为了这次分析 你把它并入了治疗表里
And here's what that adverse reaction column
把不良反应列并入治疗表中
attached to the treatments table looked like.
看起来就像这样
Here are the pandas grouped by object.
这是用 pandas 的 groupby 函数分组处理后的对象
Some of the common adverse reactions are cough, headache nausea,
其中有些常见的不良反应是咳嗽、头痛、恶心
a big one is hypoglycemia which is low blood sugar caused by
最大的反应是低血糖症
an insulin overdose, usually at least.
这种低血糖症状是由过量摄入胰岛素造成的 最起码通常是这样的
Between the two drugs, Auralin and Novodra,
在 Auralin 和 Novodra 两种药物之间
the peer counts of each adverse reaction are pretty similar.
每种不良反应的人数都差不多
With the exception of throat irritation for Auralin, the oral insulin,
除了口服胰岛素 Auralin 会造成咽部不适
which can be expected because this pill is taken
不过这点在意料之内 因为这种药丸是口服的
orally and passes by the throat before it gets to the stomach.
在到达胃部之前会先经过喉咙
And then injection site discomfort for Novodra which is the injectable insulin.
而注射型胰岛素 Novodra 则会造成注射部位不适
And again, that's to be expected because that's
这也是能预见的
a common known adverse reaction for injectable insulin because of needles.
由于要使用针筒 所以这是注射型胰岛素常见的不良反应
This is actually one of the big reasons why we want oral insulin in the first place.
这也是我们想用口服胰岛素的一大原因
And these counts are more clear in these horizontal bar charts.
这些统计数据在横向条形图中更为明显
This one for Auralin and this one for Novodra.
这一个是 Auralin 的 这一个是 Novodra 的
And let's zoom out for that comparison.
我们缩小一点以便对比
Now the next key metric,
下一个关键指标
Pre-trial Post-trial Mean Insulin Dose Change.
试验前/后胰岛素平均剂量变化
This is important because if the new oral insulin
这一指标很重要 如果新型口服胰岛素
requires a way higher dosage to be effective,
需要特别大的剂量才能生效
the manufacturer might not bring this to market.
制造商可能就不会把它推出市场
Requiring massive doses makes things financially
因为特大剂量从经济角度看是不可行的
infeasible and essentially an economic problem for the manufacturer.
而对制造商来说 这本质上是个经济问题
Even if this was effective and could improve lives,
即便药物有效 能够提高生活质量
the drug industry is a business and it's an unfortunate reality sometimes.
但制药行业毕竟是在做生意 有时候这是个很不幸的现实
So you might recall that this dosage information was
你可能还记得之前这个剂量信息
actually hidden in two columns in this treatments table,
实际上藏在了这个治疗表的两列里
Auralin and Novodra, with start dose and end dose hidden in each column,
即 Auralin 和 Novodra 这两列 每一列都藏着起始剂量和结束剂量的数据
as well as the treatment value hidden in each column header.
而疗法的值则分别藏在这两列的列名里
You separated out these start doses and end doses as
你把这些起始剂量和结束剂量分开来
well as converting this from a messy to a tidy format,
并将其从一团乱麻整理成整洁的结构
by melting the treatment variable down to its own column.
也就是把疗法这个变量拆成单独的一列
And the final product looking like this: treatment start dose,
最终成果就像这样 疗法、起始剂量、
end dose, which allowed for this mean dose change analysis.
结束剂量 这样一来你才能进行这个平均剂量变化分析
And again, the results here are good for Auralin or at least they're not bad.
这里的结果也对 Auralin 有利 至少没坏处
This negative eight's a bit misleading but it's just the way the numbers were set up.
这里的 - 8 有点误导人 不过它只是数字设定的问题
This means that patients that were treated with Auralin required on average,
意思是接受 Auralin 治疗的患者
eight more units of insulin to establish a safe,
需要增加平均 8 个单位的胰岛素
steady blood sugar level.
才能维持安全稳定的血糖水平
That's compared to Novodra patients who on average required 0.4 units less of insulin,
相比起来 Novodra 的患者则需要减少平均 0.4 个单位的胰岛素
comparing their start dose and end dose, pre-trial and post-trial.
这是从两者的起始剂量和结束剂量 试验前和试验后的数据对比得出的
This isn't terrible, the fact that Auralin required eight more units,
Auralin 需要多用 8 个单位并不可怕
this is kind of expected because we knew that
而且这算是意料之内 因为我们知道口服胰岛素
oral insulin had a tougher time in getting to the bloodstream through the stomach lining,
很难通过胃粘膜进入到血液中
and eight units more isn't that big a deal.
所以多加 8 个单位不算什么
And this difference in mean dose change is more evident in this bar plot here.
平均剂量变化的不同在这个条形图里更为明显
And again that's start dose minus end dose.
再说一次 剂量变化是起始剂量减结束剂量的结果
Okay, so now the key metric HbA1c change.
好了 现在到了关键指标 HbA1c 变化了
Recall that HbA1c change is our key indicator for diabetes control.
回想一下 HbA1c 变化是糖尿病控制的关键指标
Most of our patients in this trial are starting around 7.9 percent.
本试验的大部分病人这个指标一开始都在 7.9% 左右
And if we can establish that Auralin causes a reduction in HbA1c that's
如果我们能证实 Auralin 造成的 HbA1c 水平降低
similar to the current injectable insulin standard, that's a success.
与现有的注射型胰岛素降低标准相同 那就成功了
And the way that's going to be measured is through
而衡量这一点的方法是使用置信区间
a confidence interval, which you'll see shortly.
稍后你就会看到
But the first step in getting that interval is establishing the difference in means.
不过要得到该区间 首先要建立均数差
The difference in mean HbA1c changes that is,
也就是 Auralin 和 Novodra 两者
between Auralin and Novodra.
HbA1c 平均变化的差别
And here's what the mean HbA1c reductions looked like before you cleaned.
这是你清理数据前 HbA1c 的平均降低值
Recall that the big two aims of cleaning for
回想一下 这个 HbA1c 变化列的两大清理目标为
this HbA1c change column was filling in missing values,
填补缺失值
these NaNs here i.e.
即这些 NaN
recalculating this difference.
也就是重新计算这些变化
HbA1c start minus HbA1c minus end,
即 HbA1c 起始水平减 HbA1c 结束水平
which also address these inaccurate HbA1c changes,
这也解决了这些不准确的 HbA1c 变化数据
the ones that started with 0.9.
即这个以 0.9 开头的数据
Again, these were misrecorded by whoever wrote these down.
重申一次 这些错误是记录者造成的
These 0.9s are actually 0.4s.
这些 0.9 其实应为 0.4
Before that cleaning, Novadra had a massive advantage in HbA1C reduction,
在清理之前 Novadra 在降低 HbA1C 水平方面很有优势
0.71 compared to 0.35 for Auralin.
幅度为 0.71 和 Auralin 的 0.35 相比
That's a big difference. And here's what that looks like in bar plot form.
是个很大的不同 那个时候的条形图就像这样
A big advantage for Novadra,
Novadra 有很大的优势
but again that's before cleaning.
不过这是清理前的情况
So don't be discouraged yet.
所以别灰心
And here's what it looks like after cleaning,
清理后像这样
0.40 for Novadra compared to 0.39 for Auralin. That's much better.
Novadra 为 0.40 和 Auralin 的 0.39 相比 好多了
And again, that smaller difference in means is much clear in this bar plot.
而且平均值的这种微小不同在条形图里更为明显
So these results are encouraging but clinical trial results
这样的结果很鼓舞人心 不过临床试验结果
require more rigorous statistical analysis to confirm these.
需要更严谨的统计分析来确认这一点
And specifically the stat we were looking for was this upper limit of
准确地说 我们要找的统计数据就是置信区间的上限
the confidence interval between the differences in means being less than 0.4.
我们需要一个均数差小于 0.4 的置信区间 也即区间上限应小于 0.4
Before cleaning 0.71 versus 0.35,
在清理之前 是 0.71 比 0.35
clear difference in this bar plot.
柱形图对比鲜明
And it didn't pass our non-inferiority metric.
无法通过我们的非劣效性指标
The upper limit of the confidence interval is 0.43.
置信上限为 0.43
Without assessing and cleaning this clinical trial data,
这份临床试验数据在没有评估和清理之前
Auralin would not have passed the Phase II clinical trial.
Auralin 无法通过 II 期临床试验
After cleaning though, HbA1C reduction is pretty
不过在好好清理一番后 二者的 HbA1C 下降水平已经很相似了
similar and that's confirmed in the confidence interval,
置信区间也确认了这一点
the upper limit of 0.03 roughly is way less than 0.4, so that's great.
其上限约为 0.03 远比 0.4 小 很好
Oral insulin is similarly effective to
口服胰岛素效用
injectable insulin according to this clinical trial.
与注射型胰岛素的相似 根据这次临床试验来看的话
So what does this mean?
这意味着什么？
This means our oral insulin passed Phase II clinical trials.
意味着我们的口服胰岛素通过了 II 期临床试验
Phase II trials are the hardest to pass historically.
从过去经验来看 II 期试验是最难通过的
This is a big deal.
所以这意义非凡
Historically the probability of success for Phase II trials was 31 percent.
从过去经验来看 成功通过 II 期试验的可能性为 31%
Past Phase II this means we have a good chance of making it past Phase III
而通过 II 期试验就意味着我们有很大的机会让新药通过 III 期
as well as the regulatory review process and having a good chance of making it to market.
以及监管审查流程 也很有可能成功地让新药面世
If it does, this oral insulin would be an enormous breakthrough
如果真的成功了 这款口服胰岛素会是个巨大的突破
in treating Type I and Type II diabetes patients,
对于 1 型和 2 型糖尿病患者来说就是如此
as freedom from daily injections would liberate patients,
而且这款药物能让病人免受每日注射之苦
help reduce missed doses and therefore reduce
也能减小病人忘记用药的几率
irritating and sometimes serious complications from diabetes.
从而减少糖尿病引起的恼人 甚至是严重的并发症
Great job assessing and cleaning this data,
评估数据与清理的作用太棒了
they were both vital.
它们都至关重要